campusgroups.com 2017-07-06

# Privacy Statement - CampusGroups

## Privacy policy

****Note:** CampusGroups is a product developed and owned by Novalsys, Inc.   
All mentions of CampusGroups apply to Novalsys, Inc. as well.**

**Last Updated: January 5, 2015**

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We will never rent or sell your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes;
  * We will never share your contact information with another user, unless both of you choose to contact one another;
  * Any sensitive information that you provide will be secured with all industry standard protocols and technology;

**Please read this privacy policy to learn more about:**

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by CampusGroups.
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * How you can access and change your Account information. 
  * What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information collected by CampusGroups. 
  * How to contact us.

### Information Collection

#### Registration:

In order to become a CampusGroups user, your Group/Organization must first create an account on this web site. To create an account they are required to provide the following contact information: name, email address, degree type, year of graduation.

#### Profile Information:

Once a user, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your skills, professional experiences, and networking objectives. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional, but enables you to better identify yourself and find new opportunities in the CampusGroups system. Your Profile information can only be viewed by your Group/Organization other CampusGroups users in your network. 

#### Cookies & Log Files:

Like most web sites, CampusGroups uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file which resides on your computer which allows CampusGroups to recognize you as a user when you return to our site using the same computer and web browser. Unfortunately, if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to use our website. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on the web site.

One type of cookie, known as a “persistent” cookie, is set once you’ve logged in to your CampusGroups account. The next time you visit the CampusGroups web site, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing user so you will not need to log in before using the service. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number), however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie. Additionally, if you log out of the CampusGroups site you will need to re-enter your password the next time you visit in order to log in to your account. Another type of cookie, called a “session” cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the CampusGroups site. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your web browser.

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the CampusGroups web site we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave CampusGroups. We also receive the Internet protocol 

(IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the CampusGroups service, but is not linked to personally identifiable information in any way.

### Information Use

CampusGroups is an online service dedicated to helping all types of Group/Organizations more effectively communicate with their members. The information you choose to provide on this site is used to help you describe yourself to your Group/Organization. Your Group/Organization is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. CampusGroups owns your information in the sole objective to administer it.

#### CampusGroups Communications:

CampusGroups will communicate with you through email and notices posted on this website by your Group/Organization. 

### Information Sharing

#### Sharing Information With Third Parties:

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We will never sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to any third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your information with third parties to carry out your instructions and to provide specific services. For instance, we use a credit card processing company to bill users for subscription fees. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and are bound by strict confidentiality agreements which limit their use of such information.

#### Partnering with Other Organizations to Offer Combined Services:

CampusGroups partners with other online services to give you the combined results of both services.

#### Legal Disclaimer:

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on our company or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

### Accessing and Changing Your Account Information

You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information, or to the settings for your CampusGroups account, at any time by logging in to your account on the CampusGroups website and editing the information on your Profile page. You can also close your account through the CampusGroups website. If you close your CampusGroups account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our database. To request that we close your account and remove your information please send your request to [Customer Service](https://www.campusgroups.com/product/contact-us/). Please send your request using an email account that you have registered with CampusGroups under your name. You will receive a response to requests sent to [Customer Service](https://www.campusgroups.com/product/contact-us/)[](mailto:customer_service@CampusGroups.com) within three business days of our receiving it.

### Security

In order to secure your personal information, all communications between you and the CampusGroups website are protected through secure socket layer (SSL) encryption. Please note, this is only valid for schools who have requested an SSL implemention.

### FERPA (Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act)

CampusGroups follows The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) (20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 CFR Part 99). FERPA is a Federal law that protects the privacy of student education records. The law applies to all schools that receive funds under an applicable program of the U.S. Department of Education.

FERPA gives parents certain rights with respect to their children's education records. These rights transfer to the student when he or she reaches the age of 18 or attends a school beyond the high school level. Students to whom the rights have transferred are "eligible students."

  * Parents or eligible students have the right to inspect and review the student's education records maintained by the school. Schools are not required to provide copies of records unless, for reasons such as great distance, it is impossible for parents or eligible students to review the records. Schools may charge a fee for copies.

  * Parents or eligible students have the right to request that a school correct records which they believe to be inaccurate or misleading. If the school decides not to amend the record, the parent or eligible student then has the right to a formal hearing. After the hearing, if the school still decides not to amend the record, the parent or eligible student has the right to place a statement with the record setting forth his or her view about the contested information.

  * Generally, schools must have written permission from the parent or eligible student in order to release any information from a student's education record. However, FERPA allows schools to disclose those records, without consent, to the following parties or under the following conditions (34 CFR § 99.31):

    * School officials with legitimate educational interest; 
    * Other schools to which a student is transferring; 
    * Specified officials for audit or evaluation purposes; 
    * Appropriate parties in connection with financial aid to a student; 
    * Organizations conducting certain studies for or on behalf of the school; 
    * Accrediting organizations; 
    * To comply with a judicial order or lawfully issued subpoena; 
    * Appropriate officials in cases of health and safety emergencies; and 
    * State and local authorities, within a juvenile justice system, pursuant to specific State law. 

Schools may disclose, without consent, "directory" information such as a student's name, address, telephone number, date and place of birth, honors and awards, and dates of attendance. However, schools must tell parents and eligible students about directory information and allow parents and eligible students a reasonable amount of time to request that the school not disclose directory information about them. Schools must notify parents and eligible students annually of their rights under FERPA. The actual means of notification (special letter, inclusion in a PTA bulletin, student handbook, or newspaper article) is left to the discretion of each school.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

CampusGroups may update this privacy policy. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personal information, we will send a notice to the primary email address specified in your CampusGroups account or by displaying a prominent notice on this site.

### Questions or Comments

If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy,   
please email us at [Customer Service](https://www.campusgroups.com/product/contact-us/) or contact us at:

Novalsys Inc  
902 Broadway, 6th Floor  
New York, NY 10010   
Phone: +1 (646) 797-3161
